toastmasters.org 2017-11-24

# Toastmasters International -Privacy Policy

Thank you for visiting Toastmasters International’s official website and shopping at our online store. 

Toastmasters International respects your privacy and is committed to protecting it through our compliance with this website privacy policy (“Policy”). 

This Policy describes the types of information we may collect from you or that you may provide when you visit www.toastmasters.org and our practices for collecting, using, protecting and disclosing that information. By visiting any website in the Toastmasters.org domain, you are accepting the practices described in this Policy.

This Policy applies to information we collect:

  * On our website
  * In e-mail, text and other electronic messages between you and our website 
  * Through mobile and desktop applications you download from our website, which provide dedicated non-browser-based interaction between you and our website 
  * When you interact with our advertising and applications on third-party websites and services, if those applications or advertising include links to this Policy

**

### What personal information about members and other customers does Toastmasters.org gather?

**

**_Information You Give Us:_** ** **

We collect information you provide to us on or through our website including:

  * Information that you provide by filling in forms on our website. This includes information provided at the time of registering to toastmasters.org, donating to The Smedley Fund, subscribing to services available on our website, submitting a Trademark Use Request, posting material or requesting further services. We may also ask you for information when you enter a contest or promotion sponsored by us, and when you report a problem with our website.
  * Records and copies of your correspondence (including email addresses), if you contact us.
  * Your responses to surveys that we might ask you to complete for research purposes.
  * Details of transactions you carry out through our website and of the fulfillment of your orders. You may be required to provide financial information before placing an order through our website.
  * Your search queries on our website.
  * There may be features that are developed in the future that may result in the collection of additional new information. 

For example, you provide information when you search for a product; place an order through our store; provide information to our Member Services department; provide information in your personal profile (or profiles, if you have more than one); communicate with us by phone, email, or otherwise; complete a questionnaire; or use other Toastmasters.org features. As a result of those actions, you might supply us with such information as your name (or another person's), address, and phone numbers; credit card information; people to whom purchases have been shipped, including addresses and phone number; content of emails to us; personal information (your name and any Toastmasters International honors or awards you’ve received); and financial information.

You can choose not to provide certain information, but then you might not be able to take advantage of many of our features. We use the information that you provide for such purposes as responding to your requests, customizing your future visits to the Toastmasters website and shopping, improving our website, and communicating with you.

**_Information we collect and how we collect it:_**  

We collect several types of information from and about users of our website, including information:

  * By which you may be personally identified, including your name, postal address, email address or telephone number ("personal information");
  * That is about you but individually does not identify you, such as age, gender, language preferences, expertise, date of birth; and/or about your internet connection, the equipment you use to access our website and usage details.

We collect this information:

  * Directly from you when you provide it to us.
  * Automatically as you navigate through the website. Information collected automatically may include usage details, Information Protocol (IP) addresses and information collected through cookies, and other tracking technologies.

We receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with us. For example, like many websites, we use "cookies," and we obtain certain types of information when your Web browser accesses Toastmasters.org. 

Examples of the information we collect and analyze include the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet; login to Toastmasters.org; email address; your Toastmasters.org password; computer and connection information such as browser type and version, operating system, and platform; shopping history, which we sometimes combine with similar information from other customers to create special website features; the full Uniform Resource Locator (URL) clickstream to, through, and from our website, including date and time (how you arrived, navigated through and exited Toastmasters.org); cookie number; products you viewed. During some visits we may use software tools such as JavaScript, to measure and collect session information, including page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), and methods used to browse away from the page. This information is collected in the interest of making the Toastmasters website work better for you.

The information we collect automatically is statistical data, and does not identify any individual. It helps us to improve our website and to deliver a better and more personalized service by enabling us to:

  * Estimate our audience size, browser statistics, and popularity of content and usage patterns.
  * Speed up your searches.
  * Recognize you when you return to our website.

A number of companies offer utilities designed to help you visit websites anonymously. Although we will not be able to provide you with a personalized experience at Toastmasters.org if we cannot recognize you, we want you to be aware that these tools exist. In addition, the Federal Trade Commission provides useful information about online privacy on its own website, <http://www.privacy.ca.gov/>.  

**_Information from Other Sources:  _**Third party advertisers may appear on our website from time to time. They may be able to detect that visitors to their website arrived via Toastmasters.org. However, we do not receive any information from these or other outside websites regarding your page views, purchases or any other information.

**

### What about cookies?

**Cookies are tiny bits of information that we transfer to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser to enable our systems to recognize your browser and to provide features such as your personalized profile.

The Help portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. However, cookies allow you to take full advantage of some of Toastmasters.org's most entertaining and helpful features, and we recommend that you leave them turned on.

### **How does Toastmasters use my information?**

We use information that we collect about you or that you provide to us, including any personal information:

  * To present our website and its contents to you.
  * To provide you with information, products or services that you request from us.
  * To offer and fulfill our core business purposes.
  * To fulfill any other purpose for which you provide it.
  * To carry out our obligations and enforce our rights arising from any contracts entered into between you and us, including for billing and collection.
  * To notify you about changes to our website or any products or services we offer or provide.
  * To allow you to participate in interactive features on our website.
  * Store information about your preferences, allowing us to customize our website according to your individual interests.
  * In any other way we may describe when you provide the information.
  * For any other purpose with your consent.

**

### Does Toastmasters.org share the information it receives?

**Information about our customers is an important part of our business, and we are not in the business of selling it to others. However, we may share your information for the following purposes: 

**_Toastmasters International:_**  This includes the organization’s world headquarters, which manages Toastmasters.org, as well as Toastmasters districts, divisions, areas and individual Toastmasters clubs. In keeping with our regular offline business practices, Toastmasters International will provide demographic information about Toastmasters members to these internal associates for communication purposes only.

**_Third-Party Service Providers:  _**We may employ other companies and individuals to perform functions on our behalf. Examples include fulfilling orders, delivering packages, sending postal mail and email, removing repetitive information from customer lists, analyzing data, providing website design assistance, and processing credit card payments. They have access to personal information needed to perform their functions, but may not use it for other purposes.

**_Protection of Toastmasters.org and Others:_**  We release account and other personal information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law; enforce or apply our Conditions of Use and other agreements; or protect the rights, property, or safety of Toastmasters International, our members, or others. This may include exchanging information with civil authorities, other companies and organizations in order to protect Toastmasters International and its members from illegal activities. However, this does not include selling, renting, sharing, or otherwise disclosing personally identifiable information from customers for commercial purposes in violation of the commitments set forth in this Policy.

**

### How secure is my information?

**Toastmasters International is committed to protecting the security of your personal information and maintains physical, electronic and procedural safeguards that meet industry standards to guard your personal information. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. For example, we store the personal information you provide on computer systems with limited access, which are located in controlled facilities. We protect your account information by placing it on the secure portion of our website, using firewalls and other security technology to protect our network and systems from external attacks, and requiring you to enter a unique user name and password to access your account information online. 

When we transmit highly confidential information (such as a credit card number or password) over the Internet, we protect it through the use of encryption. Toastmasters International uses industry-standard (SSL) technology to prevent unauthorized parties from viewing potentially sensitive information such as your name and address, as well as critically sensitive information like your credit card number, that you provide or access during a secure session (look for a padlock or key and chain icon on your browser).

We reveal only the last four digits of your credit card numbers when confirming an order. Of course, we transmit the entire credit card number to the appropriate credit card company during order processing.

The safety and security of your information also depends on you. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password for access to certain parts of our website, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. Passwords, registered with our website, are encrypted to ensure protection against unauthorized access to your personal information. We ask you not to share your password with anyone. We urge you to be careful about giving out information in public areas of our website. The information you share in public areas may be viewed by any user of our website. It is important for you to guard against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer. Be sure to sign off when finished using a shared computer. 

When we collect or transmit sensitive information, such as a credit or debit card number, we use industry standard methods to protect that information. However, no e-commerce solution, website, database or system is completely secure or “hacker proof.” You are also responsible for taking reasonable steps to protect your personal information against unauthorized disclosure or misuse.

**NOTE:  **Email is not encrypted and is not considered a secure means of transmitting credit card numbers.

**

### What about third-party advertisers and links to other websites?

**

Our site may include third-party advertising and links to other websites. We do not provide any personally identifiable customer information to these advertisers or third-party websites. The rest of this section offers some examples as well as information on how to opt-out of their information collection practices.

Examples of third-party advertisers and advertising companies that serve advertising content directly to your browser on certain Toastmasters.org pages may include [Atlas ](http://www.atlassolutions.com/)and [Doubleclick](http://www.doubleclick.com/). You can find out more about their information collection and use practices, including how to opt out of cookies and other collection techniques that they use, by clicking on the links to their websites in this paragraph.

These third-party websites and advertisers, or Internet advertising companies working on their behalf, sometimes use technology to send (or "serve") the advertisements that appear on our website directly to your browser. They automatically receive your IP address when this happens. They may also use cookies, JavaScript, web beacons (also known as action tags or single-pixel gifs), and other technologies to measure the effectiveness of their ads and to personalize advertising content. We do not have access to or control over cookies or other features that they may use, and the information practices of these advertisers and third-party websites are not covered by this Privacy Policy. Please contact them directly for more information about their privacy practices. In addition, the Network Advertising Initiative offers useful information about Internet advertising companies (also called "ad networks" or "network advertisers"), including information about how to opt-out of their information collection.

**

### Which information can I access?

**Toastmasters.org gives you access to a broad range of information about your account and your interactions with Toastmasters International for the limited purpose of viewing and, in certain cases, updating that information. Examples of data you can access at Toastmasters.org include your order history and personally identifiable information (including name, email, password, and your club membership history). This list will change and expand as our website evolves.  
**

### What are my options for providing information?

**

You can always choose not to provide information, although it is needed to make a purchase or to take advantage of such Toastmasters.org features as your personal profile. Consequently, if you choose not to provide information on this website, you will be unable to conduct transactions with Toastmasters International using the Internet. Alternatives for making purchases or updating your Toastmasters International records may involve using the postal or a courier service, calling Toastmasters International’s Member Services Department or visiting the store at World Headquarters in California.

You can add or update certain information on pages such as your Profile. When you update information, we may keep a copy of the prior version for our records.

**

### How does Toastmasters International use my email address?

**Occasionally, World Headquarters uses email to send messages to large groups of members. It is the most efficient and cost-effective way of sending information to large groups of people. Some of the mass emails Toastmasters members might receive from World Headquarters are: 

  * Convention promotions
  * The Leader Letter 
  * Surveys
  * Important information about Toastmasters
  * Comments from our organization's leaders

**

###  Are children allowed to visit or shop at Toastmasters.org?

**Toastmasters.org does not sell products for purchase by children. We offer very few children's products for purchase by adults. If you are under 18, you may use Toastmasters.org only with the involvement of a parent or guardian. **

###  Conditions of Use, Notices and Revisions

**If you choose to visit Toastmasters.org, your visit and any dispute over privacy is subject to this Policy and our Conditions of Use, including limitations on damages, arbitration of disputes, and application of the law of the state of California. If you have any concern about privacy at Toastmasters.org, please contact us by [email](mailto:legal@toastmasters.org?subject=Legal%20Email) or regular mail (Toastmasters International, PO Box 9052, Mission Viejo, CA 92690 USA) with a thorough description, and we will try to resolve it. 

Toastmasters International strongly supports our members’ right to privacy. For this reason, we urge our visitors to read about privacy issues and laws on <http://www.privacy.ca.gov/>. This information is presented by the State of California Office of Privacy Protection (under the California Department of Consumer Affairs), and because World Headquarters is located in California, we fall under their jurisdiction in regard to the legalities surrounding privacy issues. We recommend that you read the page entitled: “How to Read a Privacy Policy,” which is useful information for viewing any website, including Toastmasters.org.

### Changes to our Privacy Policy

Our website is growing, and our Privacy Notice and the Conditions of Use will change also. We may email periodic reminders of our notices and conditions, though you should still check our website frequently to see reports on the latest changes. Unless stated otherwise, our current Privacy Notice applies to all information that we have about you and your account.

Toastmasters International may change, add, modify or remove portions of this Policy at any time, which shall become effective immediately upon posting on this page. The date the Policy was last revised is identified at the bottom of the page. It is your responsibility to review this Policy for any changes. By continuing to use our website, you agree to any changes in the Policy.

### Related Practices and Information

**NOTE (FOR TOASTMASTERS INTERNATIONAL MEMBERS):**  
By visiting any website in the Toastmasters.org domain, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy. Please note the following additional agreement:

I agree to the collection, use and processing of the personal information I provide to Toastmasters for the purposes of organization administration, payment of my dues, and inclusion of my contact information. By submitting my personal information to Toastmasters, I also agree that my information may be accessed and used by Toastmasters and its employees and agents, and will be transferred to countries that are not regarded as having adequate data protection, including to Toastmasters’ headquarters in the United States. I agree to notify Toastmasters International by [email](mailto:addresschanges@toastmasters.org?subject=Personal%20Information%20Update) of any change to my personal information, including making any requests to check, delete or correct my personal information, so that it is accurate and current. I understand that the majority of the data requested in this application is necessary for administrative and planning purposes, and that the failure to provide this information may prevent my application from being properly processed or inclusion of my contact information in the members’ directory.
